# **EVANIA TORRES**

Front-End Engineer | New York City

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Technical professional holding 3 years of work experience in education seeking to leverage interpersonal, technical, and programming skills to work as a frontend engineer. Specialize in creation of user-friendly, interactive, and visually appealing websites with experience in creations of streetwear brand, artist world tour, and hotel websites and logos using React, JavaScript, and Adobe Photoshop. Additional project experience and knowledge in MySQL, Tweepy API, Python, and Django. Educator who integrated technology for effective instructional design, increasing student engagement, educational and technical skills, and providing technical support for students, colleagues, and administration on Mac and Windows OS. Additional experience in social media content creation and marketing and graphic design, with recognition from recording artists for media creation works. Ambitious, analytical, and problemsolving oriented front-end engineer eager to leverage skills, accomplish company goals, and increase back-end engineering skills.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

K-5th Grade Teacher, P.S. 19 Judith K. Weiss, Bronx, NY

October 2020 — June 2021

- Utilized Otus, STARS Classroom, Microsoft Excel, and Google Suite to analyze and manage various data sets, such as student grades, demographic information, and attendance.
- Conducted statistical analysis to identify trends and patterns in student performance and developed recommendations based on research.
- Integrated technology with instructional learning and development of creative teaching strategies that improved student comprehension and retention.
- Collaborated with colleagues to achieve departmental goals and participated in cross-functional teams.
- Utilized Microsoft Outlook and Google Classroom to effectively communicate with students, parents, and colleagues to address individual needs and concerns.

## Student Teacher, Amalgamated Nursery School Bronx, NY

January 2020 — May 2020

- Utilized ClassDojo to analyze and manage data sets of students' progress and assessments and Microsoft Outlook for communicating with colleagues, and addressing parents questions and needs.
- Developed interactive lessons for in person and remote instruction for Pre-K students that led to an increase in student engagement and student development of ELA and math skills.

### RECENT PROJECTS

EnStock NYC: Streetwear Brand Website-Created, designed, and developed a NYC based streetwear brand named EnStock NYC. The EnStock NYC website provides clients with an understanding of what the brand stands for, how it was created, and contact information. Clients can also view information on the brands latest upcoming collaboration with the legendary Jordan brand. Logo designed in Photoshop and created based on EnStock NYC's representation of peace, fashion, and the Bronx. (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and Adobe Photoshop)

BLACKPINK BORN PINK: World Tour Artist Website— An interactive tour website designed and developed for internationally famous South Korean girl group BLACKPINK's current world tour. Clients are provided with information on BLACKPINK's current tour dates, group updates, social media profiles, individual member profiles, and latest music. The construction of the website is to provide verified information in a visually appealing way to reach not only the group's fans, but anyone who is curious to learn about who exactly BLACKPINK is. (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React)

#### CONTACT

evtorres1023@gmail.com

Portfolio

GitHub

LinkedIn

# **SKILLS**

HTML

CSS

**JavaScript** 

React

MySQL

Python

Microsoft Office

Adobe Photoshop

Mac OS

Microsoft Windows

Linux

Tweepy API

# **EDUCATION**

PER SCHOLAS

2022

Cyber Security | CompTIA

CySA+ Certified

#### **LEHMAN COLLEGE**

2018-2022

Master of Science: Early Childhood

Education

# **LEHMAN COLLEGE**

2013-2017

Bachelor of Arts: Dance

BORN PINK: World Tour Ticketing Database—An organized database closely constructed to provide clients with information on tour dates, cities, countries, and ticket sale numbers. Database information is based on the artist's North American tour stops and details the number of tickets remaining to be sold, and information on remaining ticket types such as resell or Ticketmaster platinum type tickets. (MySQL)

Hotel Greeting Page— Constructed and designed The Himmapan Hotel's greeting page where clients will be greeted depending on the time of day and are provided information on how to reserve a room. The greeting page design is based on IO Interactive's video game Hitman 3 and includes the Himmapan Hotel logo designed based on Thailand's national flower, animal, and country flag. The Himmapan Hotel's phone number was created based on Hitman 3's main character Agent 47. (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and GIMP)